

# KEREN HAPPU BETTY

- +91 9489735401
- kerenbetty93@gmail.com
- O Chennai India

# **SKILLS**

- ✓ IV Access/EJV
- $\checkmark ABG$
- ✓ BLS/ACLS
- ✓ Gastric lavage
- ✓ Splinting/Scoop board
- ✓ Helmet removal
- ✓ ECG recognition
- Suturing and dressing
- ✓ FAST /e FAST
- ✓ Endotracheal intubation
- ✓ LMA
- ✓ Cricothyroidotomy
- ✓ Handing Ventilator
- Urinary Catheterization
- Assisted ICD
- Assisted Central venous Catheter

## PROFESIONAL MEMBERSHIP

- ✓ AHA BLS & ACLS instructor
- ✓ AHA BLS, ACLS provider
- ✓ PHTLS provider

## **SUMMARY**

7Yrs & 9months of experience as AHA Instructor (Teaching) and Physician Assistant (Clinical). Secure a challenging medical position where in my skills and knowledge are put to its best care

To provide best care pre-hospital and in emergency room (ER). Keen to upgrade the skills according to technological development and recent scientific updates

Developing and upgrading simulation-based training to provide skillful orientation with realistic scenario in medical and trauma emergencies educator

### **EXPERIENCE**

### <u>01/2021 – till date</u>

Working as **AHA INSTRUCTOR** / Senior Lecturer in Panimalar Medical College Hospital & Research Institute, CHENNAI from Jan 2021 to till to date

- Teach AHA BLS & ACLS course for MBBS, Nursing, Allied health students and for health care providers
- Teach simulation-based education to the students and handles high fidelity mannequins
- Prepare and deliver lectures to students
- Prepare, administer, and grade examinations
- Represent our college as speakers and guest lectures

### 07/2016 - 01/2020

Worked from JULY 2016 to JAN 2020Center: G Kuppusamy Naidu Memorial Hospital, COIMBATORE NABH accredited hospital with **700 beds**.

Role: worked as Physician Assistant in Emergency Room

### **CLINICAL EXPERIENCE**

- Conduct patient interview, physical assessment and take medical histories from the patients in ER
- Performed or order diagnostic tests and interpret results in ER. With supervision of physician, formulate, implement treatment plans, and monitor patient's progress in ER
- I have experience and knowledge in handling cardiac, trauma emergencies
- Have ability to assess and treat emergencies and help the patients in distress

### INTERNSHIP

Completed one year internship during my undergraduate at GANGA HOSPIAL, COIMBATORE.

Designed at clinical areas, Intensive care unit, Emergency room,
Orthopedic department, Trauma unit,
Postoperative unit, Gynecology
department, Surgery department,
Medicine department, Anesthesiology
department, Physiotherapy
department.

# KEY SKILLS

- ✓ Critical thinking
- ✓ Active listening
- ✓ Coordination
- ✓ Clinical management
- ✓ Stimulation exercises (Mannequin study)

## **AWARDS**

- ✓ Secured gold medal in M.Sc. (Emergency and critical care technology)
- ✓ Secured gold medal in B.Sc. (Emergency and trauma care management)

# RESEARCH

"Prehospital assessment of stroke scale" during the period of NOV 2015 to MARCH 2016 at SRMC university, CHENNAI.

# **LANGUAGES**

**ENGLISH** 

TAMIL



### **EDUCATION QUALIFICATION**

M.Sc. Emergency& critical care technology, First Class, 73% Sri Ramachandra Medical College & Research Institute, Chennai – 600 116 (Year of passing: 2016)

**B.Sc. Emergency& trauma care management**, First Class,74% Avinashilingam Deemed University, Coimbatore – 641 043 (Year of Passing: 2010)

# **EQUIPMENT KNOWLEDGE & HANDLING**

Have acquired excellent experience in handling various equipment and high-fidelity mannequins like SIMMAN 3G,SIM MOM,NURSING ANNE SIMULATOR, Pediatrics mannequins, ALS, BLS & Airway equipment's & operating LLEAP software

## CONFERENCE AND WORKSHOP

- Attended "EMCON 2024," conducted by SEMI India in Chennai from November 7-9, 2024.
- Presented a poster titled "Advances in Emergency
  Cardiovascular Care in India: The Impact of AEDs and PAD
  Programs" at the AHA Summit on September 28, 2024.
- Attended the AHA Resuscitation and Healthcare Quality Summit Conference on September 28-29, 2024, at HICC, Hyderabad.
- Attended AHA workshop for TCC held on 27 SEP 2024 at Hyderabad, India
- Delivered faculty talk in STEPS 2024 virtual webinar on 23rd JAN 2024 at **SRIHER**
- AHA ITC Audit Secured 100% from our **ITC** on 20.09.2023.
- Organized State level workshop for Nursing Faculties on the 'TopicTrauma care' on Sep 2023.
- Delivered a Faculty talk in STEPS 2023 virtual national webinar on 22nd FEB 2023 at **SRIHER**.
- Attended workshop on developing pre-Hospital care in India on Oct 7 & 8 2022 at SRIHER in collaboration with THE ROYAL COLLEGE OF SURGEONS OF EDINBURGH.
- Delivered a faculty talk on EMS week celebration 2022 topic "Arrhythmia Recognition" on 18 July 2022 at SRIHER.
- Delivered a faculty talk topic "DKA" in STEPS 2022 virtual international webinar organized by department of Trauma care management on 24th Feb 2022.
- Delivered a faculty talk in Paramedic conference organized by Department of Emergency Medicine at SRM on Dec 9th & 10th 2022
- Attended Pre conference workshop of EMCON 2022 "Basics and Advanced Mechanical Ventilation" on Nov 21st 2022.
- Organized and participated AHA TCF course BLS,ACLS & PALS on Oct 20th – 22nd 2022 at PMCHRI

- Delivered a faculty talk on "STEPS 2019" workshop on TRAUMA LIFE SUPPORT held at SRIHER
- Attended SEPICON 2019 conference JAN 2019 at MADURAI
- E poster presentation at SEPICON "Antenatal mother S/P MVR presented to ER with acute CVA on 25.01.2019
- Attended EMCON conference NOV 2018 at BENGALURU
- NTLS (National Trauma Life Support) workshop at EMCON2018
- Attended **EMT** Conference held on JAN 2017 at KG HOSPITAL Coimbatore
- Attended workshop on "care of patients on mechanical ventilation" NOV 2014 at KMCH HOSPITAL, COIMBATORE
- Attended world head injury day workshop held on MARCH 2013 at GANGA HOSPITAL

#### **REFERENCE:**

1. Dr. T.V. Ramakrishnan HOD Accident & Emergency Department,

SRMC & RICHENNAI.

Contact no:9940046670

(Email ID: tramakrishnan2003@yahoo.co.in)

2. Dr.Dhilipan Associate Professor

Department of Emergency Medicine, KMCH Coimbatore.

Contact no :9842542502

Email ID: dhilip.kd10@gmail.com

3. Dr. Surapaneni Krishna Mohan Vice Principal & Professor,

Department of Biochemistry, Head, Department of Clinical Skills

& Simulation, PMCHRI, CHENNAI

Contact no :9789099989

Email ID: krishnamohan.surapaneni@gmail.com